CALVIN CURRY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



Software development for me has provided the greatest puzzle that I have ever solved. I am thrilled to have found an avenue that allows me to use logical thinking to solve problems, use my creativity to turn ideas into tangible applications, and challenge myself intellectually by continuously learning new concepts to further my growth as a developer. I am continuing to learn and grow more each day, and I cannot wait to begin the next chapter of my journey and turn my passion into my career.

PROJECTS

MARVEL INDEX

https://github.com/calvincurry22/Marvel-Index

Marvel Index is a full CRUD app that allows users to keep track of the Marvel comic books that they wants to purchase and read. The user can search for comics from their favorite characters and save them to a personalized reading list that can be accessed at any time. Once a comic from the user's list has been read, they can save it to a separate list that keeps track of their reading over time. Users can also chat with other users about topics of their choosing on the forum component within the app.

- Built with JavaScript, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Marvel external API for character/comic data
- Components were styled using Reactstrap and Material UI

EDUCATION

CUM LAUDE, BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINSTRATION, MAJOR IN MARKETING/SUPPLY CHAIN MGMT University of Memphis

CONTACT



github.com/calvincurry22



<u>linkedin.com/in/calvinmcurry</u>



calvincurry22@gmail.com



{cell: 731-616-4229}

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School (Nashville, TN) | Feb 2020 - present

Intensive full-time 6-month software development bootcamp learning with both individual andteam-based projects. Tech Stack includes: C#/.Net, React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and SOI fundamentals

- Built single-page applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and

 Poact
- Worked on team-based projects using SCRUM methodology (in-person and remote)
- Participated in pair-programming sessions (VS code Live Share)
- Practiced version control using Git and Github
- Utilized wireframing to map out UI design/structure
- Learned about one-to-many and many-to-many data relationships
- **Developed** ERDs to map data dependencies
- Learned debugging with chrome developer tools
- Utilized JSON server to access and modify data from local and external APIs

TERRITORY MANAGER

Ecolab - Kay FRS Division (Philadelphia, PA) | May 2013 - Dec 2016 (Nashville, TN) | Jan 2017 - Feb 2020

- Managed a large territory of accounts covering Southern New Jersey/Pennsylvania/Delaware and Middle TN/West TN/Arkansas/Kentucky. Trained clients on proper food safety compliance in accordance with FDA, state and local regulatory food code
- Monitored HACCP plans and OSHA compliance for accounts
- **Conducted** compliance audits for national and regional food retail establishments throughout the US
- **Submitted** daily reports using Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Concur, and internal software on a VPN server

TERRITORY MANAGER

Nestle Purina (South NJ/Philadelphia, PA) | Jan 2012 - Mar 2013

- Negotiated \$10,000+ in incremental sales volume in Q4 2012
- Used SAP to manage customer data, sales ordering, and weekly expenses
- Achieved top 5 highest independent account sales in Q4 2012
- Managed \$21MM market of national retail accounts covering North/South New Jersey with a key focus on direct selling, product training, relationship management,incremental leveraging, and inventory control.
- Analyzed business metrics to identify gaps and opportunities/prioritize tasks and objectives for each month and quarter
- **Created** and implemented marketing and sales programs to grow key brands with accounts

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

JavaScript

- C#
- HTML5
- CSS3
- React
- ASP.NET
- Git/Github version control
- SCRUM methodology

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Adaptability
- Emotional Intelligence
- Team-oriented
- Creativity
- Organized
- Time management
- Fast learner
- Motivated
- Reliable and professional